RESUME

MUTHUVEL.A

9176337648

muthuvl07@gmail.com

No:54,5th Main Road,Nanganallur,Chennai-600061

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With a successful history in the Switch Gear & Oil/Gas industry, I possess specialized skills in Production Planning, Order Processing, Inventory Management & Order to Cash operations. My qualifications include a Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) in Mechanical Engineering, and I am committed to providing exceptional operations expertise.

EXPERIENCE

Accenture Operations (Project:US Based Oil & Gas Company) *Analyst*

2021-Present

- Uses the Client web application linked to SAP and performs Sales order reconciliation of Oil Well Cementing Orders.
- Created sales orders through client application and updated material technical specifications based on engineer requirements for upcoming planned jobs, enabling the warehouse team to load materials accurately and on time for job execution.
- Ensure accuracy of booked **Sales orders, Sales contract, and Sales account data** in the Workflow systems, Verified and made necessary changes to meet individual customer requirements, such as **sold-to, bill-to, payer details**, and required documents, before billing the sales order and processing the delivery document in SAP for approved client orders.
- Provide **Operational support** to sales and other teams with regard to the order lifecycle.
- Processes the incoming Reconciliation Requests through **Sales Force** and ensures completion before the target time.
- Collaborate with Sales and other internal teams (Finance, Legal, Operations) to resolve dayto-day issues, improve processes in order to exceed operational and performance goals.
- Performing reconciliation on completed Job based on **Quote**, **Job event log and Technical Sheets** and perform the reconciliation as per Customer signed documents & agreements.
- Verified the list of services and materials to be charged in sales orders, making changes based on the reference quote and ensuring the exact price was charged.

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

- Conducted **order reconciliation** by verifying **technical sheets**, ensuring that the exact materials used and charged in the sales order.
- Reviewed Job event log documents and collaborated with the Business Development Manager to assist in decision-making regarding compensation for customers in case of job performance issues.
- Coordinated with **Inventory/Warehouse plant** team to ensure Correct Materials was charged on Sales order and communicates incase of discrepancies to match with exact quantity that was issued to the Sales Order.
- Ensures Every day Team Case Closure in Sales Force once the **Accounting Document** generated in SAP.
- Created accrual documents at the end of each month and updated records of unbilled orders.

ONGC Petro Additions Pvt Ltd (Payroll:PSAS),Chennai

Feb 2018-June 2021

Associate

- Handled End to end Inventory Consignment Stock cycle from Stock Transfer Processing,
 Purchase Order Creation to Invoicing.
- Performed Sales Order Processing of Polymers in SOUTH Region on daily basis through SAP SD and MM.
- Communicated up-to-date information on **stock availability**, **orders placed**, **orders in transit and forecast** to meet the prospective customer requirements.
- Entered accurate data in **SAP ERP** system for all requisitions and thereby ensuring accurate billing from time to time.
- Verified Customer Details and ensuring Customer Master Details to be accurate for creating Master data in SAP.
- Supported the dealers in the field of **SAP Sales cycle** from Sales order creation, creating delivery order to invoicing.
- Provided general support for sales processing activities like order execution/ billing/dispatch details and order configuration for the assigned territory and assisting sales officers.
- Maintained and Conducted inspection the inventory at the 6 Stock Points in Tamil Nadu & Bangalore Regions.
- Extracted **periodic reports** to **analyze** the status of pending orders and thereby providing necessary assistance for smooth functioning by Coordinating with the Logistics team
- Preparation of **MIS reports** like sales, stock at local warehouse & data analysis from SAP and provides information to OPAL Regional officers for Quick Decision making.

Devi Polymers Pvt Ltd

Production Engineer

Dec 2014- Feb 2018

- Oversaw Production Process of Injection Molded Electrical & Switchgear Components & preparing Production schedule for Injection Molding Section.
- · Proficiently managed SAP Inventory Management, including goods receipt, goods issue, stock transfer, and physical inventory, while maintaining accurate correspondence with actual inventory levels.
- · Aided in Drawings and 3D Part Modeling of Injection Mould parts using CAD Software and responsible for documentation.
- Collaborated with the Sales Manager and Production Manager to coordinate production planning and material planning in the Injection Molding Section, ensuring the achievement of production targets.
- Maintained SAP Inventory Management (Goods receipt, Goods Issue, Stock Transfer, Physical Inventory.) with correspondence to actual Inventory
- Troubleshooting process and product issues in the Injection Molding Shop floor.
- Improved Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) and streamlined work done by Operators and created awareness of following SOP.
- Oversaw raw material stock levels, developed internal procurement plans, and maintained inventories to support efficient production processes.
- Maintained and regulated 5S System in the Shop floor and worked on improvements.
- Oversaw Machine &Mold working condition and makes arrangement for maintenance if required.
- Prepared dispatch-related documentation for the movement of molds between company and tool room, ensuring efficient handling and necessary corrections.

SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE

Adaptability

Analytical

- Basics of SAP PP& SD
- Operational Support
 MS Office
- Critical Thinking
- Exposure to GD&T
- Basics in SQL

- AutoCAD (Certified)
- Solidworks (Certified)
- PRO-E (Certified)
- Unigraphics (Certified)

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Mechanical Engineering- 72.5% 2010-2014 High School-84.25 % 2009-2010 SSLC-86.20 % 2007-2008

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above details are true to the best of my knowledge.